根据地标显示
And as you can see from the locations,
凶手主要在南区 中区和东南区作案
the killer is working primarily in the Southern, Central and Southeastern,
符合这些地区流浪人员较为集中的特点
which makes sense given the concentrations of homeless in those districts.
1号3号受害者死于夜间 2号4号死亡时间为白天
Vics one and three were killed at night, two and four had daylight T.O.D.s.
警官 那个失踪的Butler先生呢?
Detective, what about the missing man, Mr. Butler?
他的下落有没有什么消息?
Is there any lead at all on his whereabouts?
还没 先生...
No, sir. We...
我们已和所有中大西洋区的警署联网
we have teletypes with every police agency in the mid-Atlantic,
并在十个州和区的停尸房进行每日筛查
we're also running daily morgue checks in ten states and the district,
尚未有所发现
but nothing yet.
凶手侧写情况怎么样?
Where are we on a profile?
我已让我们的人今天来Quantico
I've arranged for our people to travel to Quantico today.
联邦对此案全力配合
The bureau's been very accommodating.
这凶手很蹊跷啊
This is a strange one.
我听说过专门针对流浪汉的 可一般都是猥亵青少年
I've heard of people going after street people, but it's usually adolescent sadism.
- 这个性犯罪... - 是不一样
- This sexual thing... - It is different.
已经在暴力犯罪资料库上登记了  目前还未在全国其它地方出现
We put it out on ViCAP, and we have no hits anywhere else in the country.
时不时地来个怪胎这我能理解
I mean, I'm all for a little kinky shit now and then,
但啃咬流浪汉?
but chewing on a homeless fella?
你的案情报告很详尽 警探
You seem to be well grounded in the case file, detective.
还需要什么吗?
What else do you need?
我们已列出一张大致名单
Well, we've developed a rough list of those adult males
记录了嫌疑人打出最后一通电话后
who were briefly detained by police near pier five
警方在5号码头短暂截留的成年男性
soon after the suspect made his last call.
希望能对这些人加以监视
We'd like to put some of those under surveillance.
他们虽不是嫌疑犯 但可能是案件相关人员
They're not suspects but we would consider them persons of interest.
同时也拟出了这三区白人
We've also developed a rough list of known adult white
同性性侵犯者名单
homosexual sex offenders in these three districts.
在进行筛选的同时
And, as we cull that list, we would...
我们也希望能将他们纳入监视
we'd like to put some of those under surveillance, too.
- 那得有一打吧 - 没那么多
- About a dozen men. - Less, actually.
通过追溯调查应该可以排除不少人
We should be able to eliminate many of our potentials through retroactive investigation.
人手够吗?
Do you have your people?
我已让巡逻部长把Ellis Carver警司 从西区调到凶杀组来了
I've asked the chief of patrol to detail Sergeant Ellis Carver from the Western to Homicide
负责监听相关事宜
for purposes of running the surveillance element.
怎么不找事发区域警务人员呢?
Why not a man from one of the districts where the attacks occurred?
我和Carver以前在长期调查中合作过
Well, I've worked with Carver on prolonged investigations in the past,
他对监听设备的熟悉程度不容忽视
and his familiarity with surveillance tactics is relevant.
另外 在选择监听小组成员问题上
Also, I would be inclined to trust his objective assessment
我也倾向于相信他的客观判断
when choosing surveillance teams.
很好 巡逻部同意 执行部也没意见
Very good. If that works for patrol, it works for operations.
那如何保护市民呢?
What are we doing to protect people?
巡逻组和技术组在这三区已加派警车
Patrol and tactical are running extra cars in all three districts
并以流浪人员聚集地为侧重
with special emphasis on posts where the homeless congregate.
有十名便衣警探伪装成流浪汉轮班执勤
We have ten undercovers dressed as vagrants working staggered shifts.
当然还需要不少便衣警车
We're going to need good undercover cars, as well.
不过我听说车队的车都借去了Dickman街
And I'm told that motor pool expects nothing back from Dickman Street until...
哪有上哪儿找去 探员
Whatever you need, detective.
是 市长先生 但公共部门的人说...
Yes, Mr. Mayor, but we're being told by Public Works...
实在不行去Avis 或Hertz 我管不着 人一个个失踪呢 (均为大型连锁汽车租赁公司)
Go to Avis if you have to, Hertz. I don't give a shit. People are disappearing.
要死人了 老天啊 该干嘛干嘛去
They're dying, for Chrissake. Just do what you need to do.
坏消息 先生们
The bad news, gentlemen,
这下我们非抓住这混蛋不可了
is we're actually going to have to catch this motherfucker.
好消息是市长终于觉得公安部门
The good news is that our mayor finally needs a police department
比教育部门重要了
more than he needs a school system.
* When you walk through the garden *
火线重案组 第五季 第8集
the.wire.s05e08
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
www.1000fr.net presents
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
谎言不是事实的另一面 它就是谎言 - Terry Hanning
你好 需要些什么?
Yo, can I help you?
- 我想找点活干 - 这儿?
- I'm looking to work. - Here?
嗯 你们招人么?
Yeah, you need anyone?
- 你多大了? - 18
- How old are you? - 18.
好吧 我15岁
A'ight, man, I'm 15.
我可以让你填张申请表
I can give you a form to fill out,
但我们经理是不会雇佣17岁以下人员的
but the manager, he ain't gonna hire no one under 17.
等等
Hey, yo.
你以前跟着Namond混的吧?
You used to run with the boy Namond, right?
我以前在Fayette手下干的
Yeah, I used to be on them Fayette corners.
- 哦 对 我记得你 - 嗯 烦了 你懂吧?
- Oh yeah, man, I remember you. - Yeah, I just got tired, you know?
有点厌倦了
Shit got old.
我看你还是回去再忍忍
So, I guess you need to bang a while longer,
过阵子再来看看有没有活干
then come back, see if we got something.
干嘛找我?
Why me?
怎么不找案发地区当地的警官?
Why not somebody from a district where they caught one of your homeless cases?
妙就妙在这儿
Well, there's a hitch.
这是你McNulty搞出来的闹剧
This is some fucked-up McNulty shit.
我和我的弟兄们可不想趟这浑水
I don't want me or any of my guys getting burned.
这样行不行
Look, here's the deal.
上面多给了我些资源去查流浪汉案子
Command are throwing more resources at me than I can use on my homeless stuff.
我都搞定了
I got that covered.
但Lester有了Marlo Stanfield的新线索
But Lester's got a fresh line on Marlo Stanfield,
需要人手去查
and he needs people to run it down.
新线索?
A fresh line, huh?
不就是监听个号码么
He's got a fuckin' wire up is what you mean.
不是监听的事儿...
No, there's no wire...
你忽悠谁呢?
Who the fuck are you kidding?
我两星期前才给了他Stanfield的新手机号
I handed him a fresh cell number for Stanfield not two weeks ago.
听着 监听的事我一无所知
Listen, I don't know anything about any wire.
总之就是他有了Marlo的新线索
I'm just saying he's got a new line on Marlo,
需要人手去追查
and he needs people to run it down.
头头彻底封杀他了?
Bosses stiff-armed him?
天啊
Jesus.
这家伙在空屋里抛尸了那么多混蛋
Guy drops all those motherfuckers in the vacants.
是啊
Yeah.
你调人去帮Lester 钱从你这案子里出 是这样吧
So you're throwing people over to Lester, and paying for it from your case, is that it?
加班限令去死吧
O.T. Out the ass.
- 书面文件怎么办? - 这我会处理
- What about the paperwork? - I'll take care of that.
所有表单 工作报告 都由我来写
All the sheets, office reports, come through me.
你的人只管出警就行
All your people got to do is straight police work.
Daniels让我放手从各区抽调人员
Daniels gave me a free hand to pull people from any district.
你只管给我派几个能干活的
Just make sure you send me people who work.
McNulty
用车怎么办?
What about cars?
局里有市区商业租车的账号
Departmental account at Enterprise downtown.
要啥尽管说
Get what you need.
公共工程车辆维护再拖三个月
We delay fleet maintenance for Public Works over the next three months.
扫雪车砍一半 祈祷今年温室效应
We cut snow removal in half and pray for global warming.
这些足够这季度不用砍教育预算了
That's enough to avoid any cuts in school funding for this quarter.
这样警务行动就够用了是吧?
This funds police operations fully, correct?
一切回到从前 没有削减经费时候
They're back to where they started.
也差不多了 我们避免了教师下岗
It's time anyway. We ducked the teacher layoffs,
三年级统考分数提高了15分 不错了
and you got the 15 points on the third-grade M.S.A.s. You can live with that.
但本季度和下季度犯罪率再不降 你就吃瘪了
But if we don't drop crime in this quarter and the next, you are vulnerable.
现在不动更待何时
It's now or never.
再说 流浪汉案件你义不容辞
Besides, you're getting traction in this homeless thing.
昨天州长接受YPR电台采访 Steiner还就州里削减预算提出质疑
Governor was on Y.P.R. Yesterday, and Steiner laid him out for the state cutbacks.
流浪人员保健中心邀请市政厅明晚前去
Health Care For The Homeless have asked for City Hall's steps tomorrow night.
- 烛光悼念仪式 - 你同意了吧?
- Candlelight vigil. - You said yes, right?
Norman说若能让我抽空 点评几句也未尝不可
Norman told 'em they could do it if I got a chance to say a few choice words.
说曹操曹操到
Speak of the devil.
我刚接到华盛顿邮报电话
I just got off the phone with the Post.
那记者让你就PG县Dobey一事作出评论
Reporter there wants your comment on a story he's working about Dobey, down in P.G.,
据说他试图在民主党初选中与你角逐
looking to take you on in the Democratic primary.
什么? Dobey也要参选?
What? Dobey's getting in?
更糟的是 Upshaw出来说 他有可能代表县里表决支持
Make matters worse, Upshaw's telling people he might just throw in with said county exec.
妈的 PG这下子是要平地大暴动了
Shit, we might have a full-blown P.G. Insurrection on our hands.
- 这唱的是哪出啊? - 那里不少黑人心怀不满啊
- Why would they do that? - Lots of pissed off black folks down there.
抱怨着总是为他人做嫁衣
Lot of grumblin' about always a bridesmaid, never the bride.
Dobey不可能拿下州府的
No way can Dobey take the statehouse.
搞了半天只会浪费我们在大选上的钱
All he's gonna do is make us spend money we'll need in the general.
我们上个月去PG访问 你见了谁?
When we went a-calling in P.G. Last month, who'd you see?
Steny
Steny.
Maloney Miller 这几个人
Maloney, Miller, those guys.
白人 白人 白人
White, white and white.
连杯咖啡都没跟老Upshaw议员喝
Not even a cup of coffee with poor old congressman Upshaw.
又不是我躲着他
I wasn't snubbing the guy.
那些人受够了我们目中无人
Folks there are tired of being taken for granted.
- 我得抱佛脚去了是吧? - 抱佛脚怕都还不够呢
- Fuck, I gotta kiss a ring, don't I? - More than a ring, actually.
无限制加班?
Unlimited O. T?
上头是这么说的
That's what I'm told.
可你说又不一定是办流浪汉案子
But you say we might not be working the homeless cases.
不全是
Not all the time.
重案组有件涉毒案也需要监听监视
Major crimes has a drug investigation that may also need surveillance work.
管他什么活呢 老子反正缺钱
Shit, who cares what we work? I need the money.
好 你们暂归凶杀组 向McNulty探员汇报
A'ight then, you'll be working out of homicide. Report down there to Detective McNulty.
哦 对了
Oh, yeah.
租来的车在后边停着呢
Rented wheels on the back lot.
真不错哇!
Fuckin' A!
哇 这也太赞了吧
Ah, man, this is beautiful.
哇靠
Hell, yeah.
这事儿太妖了 竟然跟死变态聊上了
It's weird shit, talkin' to a psychopath like that.
我还采访过Dick Cheney呢 (小布什时期美国副总统)
I interviewed Dick Cheney once.
你怎么看 Gus? 这事儿是炒作 还是就像Templeton写的那样?
What do you think, Gus? Are we hyping this, or is Templeton writing as it lays?
警方说确有其事
Police say it's real.
他收到的那些照片? 那人不失踪了么
An' those photographs he got sent? The guy's fucking missing.
我看这流浪汉案件得写到12月了吧?
I guess we're writing homeless stories till December?
为什么到12月?
Why till December?
普利策奖递申年底截止
Pulitzer submissions run the calendar year.
报社在圣诞期间看得比命还重要的
Anything a newspaper cares about at Christmas,
一过了新年就狗屁都不如
they give a fuck about by New Year's.
那就跑流浪汉案呗 同志们
Homelessness it is there, gents.
等等
Hold on.
大堂有人想找个编辑谈谈
Fella in the lobby wants to talk to an editor.
什么编辑?
What kind of editor?
负责流浪汉案子的编辑
The kind that worked on the story about that homeless vet.
Scott的新闻? 你确定不是找Scott的?
Scott's piece? Sure they don't want to talk to Scott?
他说Templeton不肯接他电话
Says Templeton won't take his calls anymore,
他才亲自跑来找别人谈的
so he walked over here to talk to somebody else.
跟他说有人下去接他了
Tell him someone's coming down.
他就说了这些?
That all he say?
就走过来说他干掉了Savino
Just walked up and said he got Savino.
他说要是Marlo不上街跟他当面对峙 他还要抓走我们更多兄弟
Said he gonna get more of our muscle if Marlo don't come to the street and step to him.
幸好在Monk家他没把我认出来
Good thing he didn't make me from Monk's apartment.
我拼命把脸转开 就怕他记得我
I kept on lookin' away from the motherfucker, hopin' he ain't remember me.
他还一瘸一拐的
He was limpin' bad, too.
拄着个拐杖
He had a crutch.
Savino那事儿怕不是吹的吧
Wasn't lyin' about Savino, was he?
大家都说Omar复仇来了
Everybody sayin' Omar's on this warpath.
听说他上周劫了个毒窝 大家都...
Heard he got a stash house last week. Everybody's...
大家都他妈该闭嘴了
Everybody need to shut the fuck up.
我只觉得 Jungbug胡说两句Marlo都发飙
Look, I'm just sayin', if Marlo was all that over June Bug callin' him a name,
让你们把他家满门抄斩 那这算啥?
so that y'all dropped June and his whole family, then what the fuck?
Omar每天把他骂得狗血淋头
Omar out there callin' 'em bitches every damn day.
Omar去死
Fuck Omar.
怎么 你不信我们会抓住这死基佬?
What, ya think we ain't gonna catch this dicksucker?
这黑鬼就等死吧
This nigger gonna get got.
你们会告诉Marlo么?
Y'all gonna tell Marlo?
告诉他 告诉他干嘛
We tell him, we don't tell him.
他要操心的事儿够多了
Man got enough on his plate.
这小子是有意见啊怎么的
Young on some different opinion shit there.
我不知道 可我要是Marlo...
I dunno. If I was Marlo...
你妈 你丫不是他
Motherfucker, you ain't.
树莓?
Raspberry?
野草莓
Wild strawberry.
- 怎么了? - 没什么
- What? - Nothing, man.
干嘛 要跑老远呢
C'mon, man, we gotta get across town.
这家伙能告诉你哪儿在施工
This bitch is gonna tell you where there's construction,
哪儿左转 哪儿右转
gonna tell you left, gonna tell you right.
好好问它什么都知道
Pretty much blow you if you ask nice.
看
And look.
哇 必须来点经典R&B哇
Yo, you gotta play some old school R'n'B shit on that, man.
新车 加班费 有这些好处
New car, O.T. This fuckin' detail, man.
真希望永远也抓不到那死变态
I hope we never catch this goofy motherfucker.
警官们 跟你们说哦
Hey, officers. Lookee here.
那边街角有俩小子
You got two young bucks round the corner.
一个穿白T恤 另一个穿背心
One in the white tee, the other guy a throwback on.
一个裤裆里藏着枪 另一个有把刀 懂吧?
One got the jump in his dip and the one with a car tire, ya feel me?
- 街角那儿? - Fulton和Lex拐角
- Round the corner? - Fulton and Lex.
- 好吧 - 谢了
- A'ight. - Thanks, man.
Hanning先生? 很高兴您能来 先生
Mr. Hanning? It's an honour for me to meet you, sir.
- 你谁啊? - 我叫Gus Haynes
- Who are you? - My name's Gus Haynes.
- 关于您的报道是我编辑的 - 那你就他妈在撒谎
- I edited the story you're featured in. - Then you're a fucking liar.
Omar Omar来了!
Omar. It's Omar, yo!
赶快丢下东西滚
Gotta giddy up an' go, dawg.
滚!
Get!
一
One...
二
Two...
三
Three...
四
Four.
看见没 Omar知道藏哪儿
Ya see there? Omar know what one it is.
怎么 干活儿的都害病躲起来啦
Look like all your muscle done up and indisposed now.
识相的快把东西交出来 听见没?
So you might as well go ahead and drop it out, ya feel me?
别逼我冲进去
I'm obliged to walk up in there now.
你们替Stanfield干活
You workin' a Stanfield corner,
就是替超级孬种干活
which means you workin' for a straight-up punk.
明白么?
Ya feel me?
老子可是每天在大街上走
I'm out here in these streets every day.
老子要命一条
Me an' my Ionesome.
他丫的人呢?
An' where he at?
你们去告诉他
Yo, y'all put it in his ear.
Marlo Stanfield别想在这城里混  听见了?
Marlo Stanfield is not a man for this town. You dig?
八个人四辆车 Ellis交代过了
Yeah, eight men, four cars. Ellis briefed 'em.
他们知道怎么回事的
They know what's what.
没事儿 他们很高兴有加班费拿 别担心 Lester
No, they're just happy for the O.T. Don't worry, Lester.
你他妈快签了 赶紧闭嘴吧
Just sign the motherfucker and shut the fuck up.
给我
Gimme.
能走了吧?
We ready?
这时候上环城高速不提前一个小时不行
'Cause you gotta figure an extra hour to get round the Capital Beltway this time of day.
你以前接受过FBI侧写么?
You ever done an FBI profile before?
- 一次 - 怎么样?
- Once. - How'd it go?
把卷宗拿去照着念一遍 没啥新鲜玩意儿
They take your file, read you back some shit you already know.
- 那还找他们干嘛? - 这样才能对上头交代嘛
- Then why do it? - So that we can say we did.
来包Newport烟
Need a pack of Newport.
软包的
Soft pack.
这也给我来一个
Let me get one of them, too.
别开枪!
Don't shoot!
Lowenthal 人呢?
Lowenthal. Where the fuck is he?
他...
He's...
来了 Bunk
There you go, Bunk.
DNA比对申请表
Request for a DNA comparison.
06H-271号案件
Case 06H-271.
潜在证据与已有样本对比
Latent trace to obtained samples.
这事儿跟流浪汉谋杀案有关
And it's a part of the serial killer thing.
已经正式成为该案一部分了
It's now a part of that investigation.
是该另当别论 既然都跟那案子沾边了...
That's different. If it's connected to that investigation...
没错 给
It is, here.
- 我笔记里写着 - 我从没说我遇到的是交火
- It's in my notes. - I never said I was in a firefight.
- 那天绝对不是 - 你明明说了
- Not on that day. - Sorry, but you did.
我跟你说领头的车撞上了自制炸弹
I told you the lead vehicle took a hit from an elevated I.E.D.
炸死了前排战士 炸飞了司机的双手
Killed the 50 gunner, and blew the hands off the driver.
就这样 没了
That's it. That's enough, man.
- 你后面瞎编什么瞎编? - 我编什么了我
- Why make the rest of that shit up? - I didn't make anything up.
- 我们好好地坐着喝咖啡 - 咖啡
- We sat there having coffee. - Coffee.
- 吃甜甜圈喝咖啡 你说... - 我说什么了?
- Having donuts and coffee. And you said... - What I say?
- 让我说完行吗? - 我不知道
- Can I finish? - I don't know.
只听你说咖啡和甜甜圈 没听你说...
I'm hearing about coffee and donuts, I'm not hearing...
让我说完 如果你不让我讲我对事实的理解...
If you're not going to let me tell my side of the story...
谎言不是事实的另一面 说谎就是说谎
A lie ain't a side of the story, it's just a lie.
- 我不想听你的污蔑 - 好了 你先别着急
- I don't have to listen to this. - OK. Scott, let's just relax here.
你们两位 大家都退一步嘛?
Both you gentlemen, let's just step back here, please?
Hanning先生 请原谅 您酗酒吗?
Now, Mr. Hanning, forgive me, but do you drink much?
我他妈不喝酒会去睡桥洞?
You think I fucking sleep under a bridge sober?
有时候我喝多了 谁不爱喝两杯嘛
Sometimes when I have a few, and I do like to have a few,
但是讲起故事来就不免添油加醋了点
I tend to be a little more descriptive in the telling of a tale.
我知道什么是添油加醋
I know what it is to tell a story.
老子当年什么没吹过
I've told plenty in my time.
但有些事发生了 决不能胡编乱造
But there's some things that happen, you don't ever fuck with them.
Scott
我相信你 Hanning先生
I believe you, Mr. Hanning.
我相信你是这么认为的
I believe that you believe.
你认为你讲的是一回事
That you believe you told me one thing.
但先生 不是不尊重和感激您
But, sir, with all due respect and gratitude,
和您为这个国家做出的牺牲
for you and the service you gave to this country,
但你当初讲的不是这样
you didn't tell me that thing.
你讲的完全是另一回事
You told me something else.
我完全按照他说的写的
I wrote Mr. hanning told me.
- Hanning先生 我知道你... - 万一哪个人
- Mr. Hanning, I know you... - What if one of the guys,
万一当时在场的海军陆战队员 看到你瞎编的这些东西?
what if a Marine who was there, he reads that shit that you made up?
我看不下去今天才来的 万一他们看到怎么办?
That's why I come down here today. What if one of the guys sees that?
别让我看见这家伙
Man, get him outta my face.
这家伙疯了
Guy's just off.
不是真疯 就是吃错药了 反正疯了
Off in general, off his meds. I don't know, but off.
- 好多都不正常 不是我说什么... - 故事倒是头版的好材料
- A lot of them are, you know. I hate to say it... - He puts on a good front.
我们给陆战队打电话 查服役记录
We'll call the Marines, get a service record,
找找他小队的其他人  看看到底发生了什么...
reach out to some people in his unit, find out what happened that day outside of...
- 哪儿来着? Fallujah? (伊拉克城市) - 对
- What was it? Fallujah? - Yeah.
要是确实像你写的那样 这事儿就算了
If it went down the way you said, we'll let it be.
要是不对 就当是一场误会
But if not, we'll chalk it up as a misunderstanding.
不管是不是误会 要是真的报道失实 我们必须发表勘误
But misunderstanding or no, we will write a correction if what we printed wasn't accurate.
我们喝的也不是咖啡
And we didn't have coffee.
喝的是巧克力奶
We had chocolate milk.
你怀念以前的生活么?
You miss what you had, though?
我还没折腾够 不想就这么安定下来
I still got too much dog in me to be settled like that.
不是Cheryl的问题 是我
It wasn't Cheryl. It was me.
我跟她儿子倒挺合得来 怪吧
Thing is, is I found a connect with the boy, you know?
看见他心里踏实
That part of it feels right to me.
小孩是挺好
Kids are great.
嗯
Yeah.
你跟Beadie呢? 好久没听你提起她了
What about you and Beadie? You were quiet there for a time.
Bunk有次跟我说 我跟身边人犯冲
Yeah. Bunk once told me I'm no good for people.
逮谁害谁 他说
Everyone around me, he said.
- 他醉了吧? - 是 不过一样
- Was he drunk? - Yeah. But still.
- Omar死翘翘啦 姐跟你说 - 不是早说他死了嘛
- Omar be dead. I'm tellin' you. - Heard that before.
- 这次真的 - 你看见了?
- For real. - You see him?
看着他直挺挺地躺在那儿呢
Seen his dead ass layin' right up in there.
街角小子说他想去抢劫韩国人 被崩了
Boy up on the corner say he try to rob them Koreans and got killed.
你该让我把他送牢里去的 Bunk
You shoulda let me give him the years, Bunk.
他也不至于如此下场
He'd have been better off.
谢谢你们叫我来
Thanks for calling.
估计你会想亲眼看看  毕竟你跟这家伙关系不一般
Figured you'd wanna see this, you being so tight with the mope.
专业的手法呐
Professional job here.
不是 我一开始也那么想 可送回局子里的韩国店主说
No. I thought so at first, but the Korean broad we sent downtown
杀他的是个拿着大枪的小矮个子
said he got done in by a short little fella with a big gun.
靠 冲进来就把他咯蹦了
Shit, walked in an' lit his ass up.
多矮?
How short?
那孩子还抢了他?
The boy robbed him?
柜台女的说小混混都冲进来抢纪念品
Counter lady said the hoppers all ran up in here for souvenirs.
他的散弹枪和半自动步枪也拿走了
Took his shotty and his semiauto too.
兜翻了个底朝天
Ran all through his pockets.
随意
Be my guest.
复仇来了 是吧?
Back on the hunt, were you?
小子说他没开车 一瘸一拐地在大街上走
Young 'un say he out here with no car, walkin' with a limp an' shit.
他死定了 Chris 你等着瞧
He gonna fall, Chris. You gonna see.
- Marlo要见面 - 真的?
- Marlo need a meet. - For real?
Leander 怎么样了?
Leander, where we at?
还在安排编组 怎么 你又截到信息了?
Still setting this up. Why, did you catch another one?
6:55和34
6:55 and 34.
还没正式监视呢 从明天起再说吧
We're not on anybody yet, so we'll pick it up in the morning.
- 好吧 回见 - 再见
- All right, later. - All right.
好 Doze Truck 你跟Monk Metcalf
OK. Doze, Truck, you're on Monk Metcalf.
Bobby 你和Brian跟Chris Partlow
Bobby, you and Brian are on Chris Partlow.
他一般坐Snoop Pearson的车
He usually rides with Snoop Pearson,
要是他俩分开 Karen和Tony就去跟她
but if they split, Karen and Tony will pick up on her.
Marcus Angela 如有需要你们作为候补
Marcus, Angela. You're the backup unit when we need one.
- 你监视Stanfield? - 嗯
- You're gonna do Stanfield? - Yeah.
他们有事都当面谈 每天在露天见好几次面
All their business is face-to-face, and they meet in the open several times a day.
我们要找出其中的规律
We're just trying to find the pattern in the meets.
从哪儿开始跟踪?
Where do we pick these guys up?
Stanfield控制着MLK到Monroe的每个街角
Stanfield has every corner between MLK and Monroe,
人差不多从11点开始到位
and they start shaping it up around 11 or so, OK?
负责送货的开始补货
That's when the re-up orders start coming in,
这时就能看见Monk开始巡逻
that's when you'll start to see Monk making the rounds.
一般早上 Marlo会开一两个晨会
Most mornings, Marlo starts off with a parley or two
地点在Mosher和Lanvale街之间的操场上
on the playground between Mosher and Lanvale.
他们好像也做批发生意
Now, these guys seem to be wholesaling, too.
其他毒贩 打手 但凡想见他的都去那儿见
Other dealers, players, anyone who wants to get with him gets him there, OK?
Chris和Snoop一般和他一起
Chris and Snoop are usually with him.
McNulty会搞定书面报告的
And McNulty's got you covered for paperwork.
我们干的这些都不用上报法庭
None of what we do here is necessary for court,
就别费心了 明白吗?
so rest easy on that, all right?
我们明天九点在此会合
So we stage here tomorrow at nine.
没见他 不过抓不到他我誓不罢休
No sign of him, but I ain't on nothin' else for as long as it take.
你没听说? Omar嗝屁了
You ain't heard? Omar bagged up.
还以为你们会跑来告诉我呢
Shit, I thought y'all was gonna tell me.
我刚听Monk说的
I just got the word myself from Monk.
- 谁干掉他的? - 一小男孩儿
- Who got him? - Some young boy.
- 谁? - 名字不知道 连为什么都不知道
- Who? - Ain't heard a name. Don't even know if there was a why.
混混听到枪响 就见他死了
Hopper wanna hear a pop, see the damage, ya know?
好 这事儿算是结了
Yeah. That shit is gone.
等我们下次补完货
We done with this next resupply,
咱去大西洋城逍遥一下如何?
you an' me got some time in AC coming to us, don't we?
法证学上来讲 这家伙什么都沾点边儿
Forensically, this guy is all over the map.
有性犯罪 但呈现抑制行为
Sexual to a point, but inhibited.
部分犯罪夜间发生 部分白天
Nocturnal on some, diurnal on the others.
再加上仅仅针对流浪汉这点?
And the notion of targeting the homeless, to begin with?
我们虽只见过一两次
We've only seen that a couple of times,
但那些案例中 罪犯本身也是其中一员
but in those instances, it's been someone within that cohort.
不太会携带手机 还给报社打电话
And they're not usually carrying cellphones and calling newspapers.
这家伙很奇特啊
You caught a strange one here.
探员们 别站起来
Detectives. Don't get up.
我是Arthur Toland 分析组副组长
Arthur Toland, deputy director of the unit.
我过来就是想问问 我的人对你的案情还算有帮助吧
Just wanted to drop by and make sure we're progressing your case.
受益匪浅 多谢了
Yeah. Great. Thanks.
你们可能在电视上见过组长
You might recognize the director from television.
- 上镜都是他去的 - 你们知道那些新闻栏目的嘛
- He's done all of them. - You know those news shows.
有什么案子总要找个出来说话的
Always want a talking head when a case comes up.
皆为美国谈话类节目主持人
Greta van Susteren Nancy Grace  Chris Matthews
Greta van Susteren, Nancy Grace, Chris Matthews,
那个寿星额头的 叫啥来着?
that fella with the big forehead, whatshisname?
- Larry King? - 对
- Larry King? - Yeah.
管他呢 总要有人代表局里说说话嘛
What the hell. It's a chance to get the word out for the bureau.
我还出过几本书
And I sell some books.
"终极猎人 - 美国连环杀人犯的崛起"?
"Human Hunters - The Rise of the American Serial Killer"?
"CSI"里用了我不少案例
They've used a lot of my stuff on those CSI shows.
我给他们做顾问来着
I've consulted for them.
你们没听说过...
You haven't heard...
你干凶案组多久了?
So, how long you been doing death investigations?
八年了
Eight years.
我们那儿连环谋杀案还真不多
We don't see a lot of serial stuff, actually.
都是毒品案 街头抢劫什么的
Drug murders. A street robbery every now and then.
一年300来起
300 or so a year.
现在这不有了嘛 那我就不打扰你们了
Well, you've got a serial case now, so, I'll leave you to it.
狩猎愉快
Good hunting.
Art是"炸弹客"一案的首席调查员 (卡钦斯基炸弹案)
Art was lead investigator on the Unabomber thing.
那得是16年前了吧?
That was, like, 16 years, right?
对
Yeah.
后来是他兄弟把他供出来的吧?
Then his brother ratted him out?
流浪汉排给30英寸版面
Homeless is in at 30 inches.
写得不错啊
It's good shit there.
真的
No, really.
场景感很强 尤其是汉诺威大桥下
There was a real sense of place, especially under the Hanover Bridge
警察过来提醒大家那段
when the police came up under there to give the warning.
小细节 大味道
Drama in small moments like that.
- 其实我有个导游 - 哦?
- Truth is, I had a tour guide. - Yeah?
嗯 我在施粥棚遇见的家伙
Yeah, fella I met at a soup kitchen.
在那儿做志愿者 前吸毒人员
Volunteer there. Ex-addict.
这家伙身上有种 我觉得他...
There's something about this guy. I mean, he's just...
说不清 越听他讲 越觉得他才值得我写
I don't know, the more he talked, the more I felt like it was him I really wanted to write about.
- 是吗? - 但他不是流浪汉
- Yeah? - But he's not homeless.
我没正式采访他  连他到底有啥经历都不知道
I don't have any peg for him. Shit, I don't know what the story is.
- 叫啥名字? - Reginald Cousins
- He's got a name? - Reginald Cousins.
在施粥棚做志愿者 靠啥挣钱?
Volunteers at a soup kitchen. What's he do for money?
每天早上沿着Light街卖《太阳报》
Sells the Baltimore Sun every morning out by Light Street.
- 哈 这可不是啥好买卖 - 他住在他姐姐家地下室
- Shit. Not exactly a growth industry. - He lives in his sister's basement.
她有时候端点饭菜下去 但是不许他上楼
She'll take a plate down to him now and then but won't let him upstairs.
- 花点时间跟他聊聊 - 流浪汉的案子怎么办?
- Spend some time with him. - What about the homeless coverage?
别担心 花两个星期 看看有什么故事?
You're covered. Take a couple weeks, see what you see. A'ight?
警方最新消息
Late entries from the copshop.
Charles县一家着火两人死亡 市区一起谋杀案
Two dead in a Charles county house fire, and a homicide from the city.
Ettlin 还有多少版面?
Ettlin, what do we got room for?
都市摘要还缺一篇简报
We're shy one brief in the metro digest.
四段就差不多了
Four paragraphs'll fill.
凶杀案什么来头?
What's the homicide?
34岁黑人男性在西区杂货店中枪身亡
A 34-year-old black male shot dead in West Baltimore grocery.
嫌疑人似为青少年
Juvenile suspect is being sought.
写火灾吧
Write up the fire.
谋杀案算了 没版面了
Scratch the murder, we don't have room.
根据已知法证做出行为分析如下:
So what we conclude from a behavioral analysis of the known forensics is the following:
嫌疑人似为白人男性 年龄在近30-近40间
The suspect is likely a white male, in his late 20s to late 30s.
很可能从未上过大学
He likely is not a college graduate,
但自认为比那些受过高等教育的人优秀
but feels nonetheless superior to those with advanced education,
有可能受雇于官僚机构
and he is likely employed in a bureaucratic entity,
政府部门或准公共部门 感觉受到排挤
possibly civil service or quasi-public service, from which he feels alienated.
他对权威不满 并对横加干涉他工作的人
He has a problem with authority and a deep-seated resentment of those
怀有强烈的憎恨
who he feels have impeded his progress professionally.
轻微的性行为显示出这并非犯罪的初衷
The minimized sexual activity suggests that this is not a primary motive for the killings.
最新一具尸体上的咬痕缺乏唾液DNA
In fact, the bite marks in the last found victim lacking the DNA of saliva,
显示出这可能是死后伪造
indicate to us possible post-mortem staging.
嫌疑人很难与人保持长期关系
The suspect has trouble with lasting relationships
并可能为高功能酗酒者
and is possibly a high-functioning alcoholic,
在这些犯罪中酒精起到了触发作用
with alcohol being utilized as a trigger in the commission of these crimes.
他对流浪汉的憎恨
His resentment of the homeless
可能始于 对这一群体内某人的私人恩怨
may stem from a personal relationship with someone in that cohort,
也可能选择以无业游民为犯罪对象
or his victimization of vagrants might merely present an opportunity for him
为他提供了显示智力优越性的机会
to assert his superiority and intellectual prowess.
如果有其他信息 传过来 我们会更新侧写
If you get more, fax it down, and we can update the profile.
非常感谢
Thanks for everything.
谢谢
Thanks.
觉得怎么样?
So, what do you think?
骗骗小孩子的
They're in the ballpark.
议员先生 你我之间有什么问题都好商量
??Congressman, I'll do whatever it takes to make things right between us,
但让Dobey参加党内初选只会两败俱伤
but running Dobey in the primary is only gonna hurt everybody.
- 是你自身难保吧 - 要打败共和党那混蛋
- You mean hurt you. - I'm the only viable candidate
我是唯一适合的候选人 这点你很清楚
to beat that Republican prick, and I know you know that.
难道大家最终不都为了这个吗?
At the end of the day, isn't that what it's all about?
不用你浪费口水告诉我
Do not waste your breath tellin' me
我只知道你们减税
what I already know about our tax-cutting,
烂摊子往县里推 对州长有钱就是娘
dump-it-on-the-counties, ass-kiss-every-business-interest governor.
PG县每年有100起谋杀案
P.G. County has 100 murders a year,
教育系统勉强支撑
school system held together with spit and glue,
高峰时期交通拥堵比亚特兰大还糟
and worse rush-hour traffic than Atlanta.
除非火烧眉毛 州长鸟都不会鸟我们
And the man in Annapolis wouldn't piss on us if we were on fire.
- 您尽管说 议员先生 - 我受够那些共和党人了
- Don't hold back, congressman. - I'm tired of these fuckin' Republicans.
没早点来见你是我不对
I fucked up, not coming to see you earlier.
但凭我在巴尔的摩拉到的选票
But between the votes I can pull out of Baltimore,
加上蒙哥马利和你们县  我一定能拿下州府
Montgomery and your county, I am gonna take the statehouse.
到时你们的种种不顺必将终止
And then the frustration that you feel is gonna end.
我知道每个混蛋都这么对您说
I know you've heard this from every other son of a bitch,
但议员先生 我向你保证
but congressman, I give you my word.
你说得对 这话我听了无数遍
You know, you're right. I have heard that before.
想把PG县拉入你的阵营
You wanna keep P.G. County in your camp,
光说不练可不行
it's gonna cost you a lot more than your word.
Jimmy 未来在哪里 也许明后天回 也许不回来 想想清楚吧 B
操
Fuck.
你找我?
You rang?
你这案子有意思啊
Funny case you got here.
死者有注册地址
Your victim had an address.
有家 付房租 说不定还在还贷
A home. Paid rent, so we assume. Maybe even a mortgage.
反正肯定不是流浪汉 无勒痕无红丝带
But not homeless, in any case. No strangulation, no red ribbon.
Christopher Partlow
你这样胡来 换别人早发飙了 Bunk
A lesser man might get pissy because you jumped the line, Bunk.
我?
Me?
去年那么些案子 Partlow这名字我记着呢
I remember Partlow's name from all those cases last year.
- 恭喜 - 嗯
- Congrats. - Yeah.
不过...
But...
别再拿我开涮了
don't fuck with me like this again.
嗯
Yeah.
他在贷款申请上说谎了吧?
He lied on his mortgage application, huh?
- 名字在这儿 - 铁证 我知道
- We have a name for that over here. - The headshot. I know.
如果以贷款问题起诉 他肯定会申辩
On a mortgage charge, he's certain to plead out.
- Billy从不替客户申辩 - 那可就是好多年的刑期了
- Billy doesn't plead his clients. - Then he's looking at a lot of years.
联邦陪审团和当地那些可有天壤之别
A federal jury is a very different animal than what they see on Calvert Street.
我告诉过他了
I tried to tell him that.
但Bond先生偏要一意孤行
Yeah, but Mr. Bond wanted to try this himself,
想靠此案挤进市府
see if he couldn't grandstand his way to City Hall.
探员 你有物证 却揪不出幕后黑手啊
Well, you have the headshot, detective, but no gun with which to fire it.
- 我们不能接这案子 - 都是白纸黑字的证据
- We can't take this case. - It's all on paper.
你有空头支票 银行账户
You had canceled cheques. You had bank accounts.
你有替他洗钱的人举证
You had his bag man on the stand.
我们有市陪审团嘛
-We had a city jury. -hmm.
我们盯了Clay Davis整整六年了 探长
We've been gathering string on Clay Davis for six years, detective.
六年 终于可将这个周扒皮一举拿下
Six years, we've had a file open on that shakedown artist.
结果倒好 你们市的杂种们区区一周
And now, after you city sons of bitches have managed,in a single week,
就把他妈的Clay Davis 吹成了马丁路德金第二
to transform Clay fucking Davis into Martin Luther King Jr.,
你现在给我看这些
you now come to me with this,
你藏着掖着的早不拿出来
which you had in your back pocket all along,
现在让都是白人的联邦陪审团怎么补救啊?
looking for the federal jury of mostly white faces to remedy the problem?
唉...
Well...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢了
Thank you.
这什么?
What's this?
从一死了的劫匪兜里找到的
From the pocket of a dead stick-up boy.
Omar Little
Omar Little.
Omar? 死了?
Omar? Dead?
你通告都不看了? 昨天死在一家杂货店
You stop readin' the 24s? Killed yesterday at a grocery.
- 都没来得及拔枪 - 不会吧
- Slow to the draw, he was. - No shit.
一枪击中后脑勺 Norris和Crutchfield接报的
One to the back of the head. Norris and Crutchfield caught it.
说作案的是少年 他在追杀Stanfield团伙
They're looking for a juvenile. He was hunting Stanfield and crew.
- 在他身上找到的? - 嗯
- And this was on him? - Yep.
看到它就想起你和Lester了
Thought of you and Lester when I saw it.
就当报答你替我摆平实验室
Payback for you getting me back some great lab.
DNA显示与Chris Partlow匹配
Positive DNA on Chris Partlow.
小巷殴打致死 不是空屋案
An alley beating, not one of the ones in the vacants.
他奶奶的 你今天消息不少啊?
Motherfucker. You have all kinds of news today, don't you?
这就去申请逮捕令
Going for a warrant right now.
你能不能等等?
Hey, can you wait to serve it?
- 我们就快收网了 Bunk - 多久?
- We're right at the edge, Bunk. - How long?
这可是板上钉钉的谋杀罪
'Cause this is an honest fuckin' murder prosecution.
我会告诉Lester的 恭喜了
I'll talk to Lester. Congrats.
不蒙不骗 堂堂正正破案 怎么样 Jimmy?
Yeah. No shuckin', no jivin'. Just good ol' police work. How about that, Jimmy?
不靠我忽悠 你还不是在等实验室结果
Without my bullshit, you're still waiting on lab work.
Jimmy 西港口的Conaway枪击案?
Listen, Jimmy, the Conaway shooting from Westport?
那个异装癖? 我查了ViCAP数据库 又有一起类似案件
The transvestite? I go to ViCAP, there's another one just like it,
卡罗莱纳 四个月前
down in Carolina, four months ago.
给我辆车 报销两晚旅店 我去查查
For a road car and two nights in a hotel, I can put this down.
你说什么呢? 你那是9mm口径 这是.32
What are you talking about? Yours is a 9mm, this one's a.32.
你那起是酒吧拐带 这是入室抢劫
Yours was a bar pick-up, this one's a home invasion.
还是值得一查的嘛
Still worth checking out.
我不觉得 抱歉
I don't see it. Sorry.
你非要我明说是吧?
You're gonna make me spit it out, aren't you?
你在希尔顿Head玩过高尔夫不?
You ever played Hilton Head?
我小舅子前两天打电话给我
I get a call from my brother-in-law a few days ago.
说订到了本周末限时球道
He managed to swing a tee-time for this weekend.
Jimmy 我非去不可
Jimmy, I'm going, goddammit.
管我什么事 滚
The fuck do I care? Go.
你在这儿玩得还挺得瑟哈
You know, this is some real cute shit you're pulling here.
拿着上头专拨的款子借花献佛
Taking the detail money and doling it around like a priest passing wafers.
你葫芦里卖的什么药我不懂 我只知道
I don't know what you're up to but I know this.
只要一通电话打上去  你就他妈的死定了
If someone picked up a phone around here, your shit is critically fucked.
两晚酒店 一辆车
Two nights and a road car.
Leander Marlo手机发出10:55和34
Leander, I'm showing 10:55 and 34 from Marlo's phone.
有行动不?
Anybody on the move?
我跟踪他从Calhoun沿Baltimore街往东
I got him coming eastbound on Baltimore Street at Calhoun.
- 谁跟Monk? - 等等
- Who's on Monk? - Wait one.
23-06呼叫23-11 你们在哪儿?
23-06 to 23-11. Where you at, man?
23-11 MLK大街往南 接近40国道
23-11. Southbound MLK, approaching route 40.
要见面了 Lester Monk和Marlo在西区 我们上
That's the meet, Lester. Monk and Marlo on the westside. We on it.
Argyle和Dolphin街角
Corner of Argyle and Dolphin.
Monk和Marlo 不出所料
Monk and Marlo, as expected.
现在Marlo的手机又收到4:40和35
Now I got 4:40 and 35 coming into Marlo's phone.
他是在看手机 Lester
Yeah, he's scoping that, Lester.
那就不是Monk发的
We know it ain't Monk callin'.
- 23-06呼叫23-12 - 收到
-23-06 to 23-12. -23-12.
- 你们监视到谁? - 两个都在
- Who do you have eyes on? - Both my subjects.
- 拿着手机吗? - 否
- They go to their cellphones? - Negative.
- 在移动中吗? - 否
- They on the move? - Negative.
- 23-14 也没移动 - 没人打电话或转移
- 23-14, nothing moving either. - No one else calling or moving.
说明还有其他人联网 我们不知道
Means we got somebody else on this network we don't yet know.
啊呀
Oh, boy.
- 嘿 我来帮你吧 - 好吧 准备好了?
- Hey, man, let me give you a hand. - All right, you ready?
我现在手上没钱
I don't have no money in the moment,
不过我过一两小时要去废品回收站
but I'll be going down to the scales in a hour or two.
你帮我忙 我给你10美元辛苦费
You help me out, I'll go ten for your trouble.
你后面有块布 包扎下
Got a rag for that behind you.
收废品咯
Junk! Junkman!
收废品
Junk!
你这是去哪儿?
Where the fuck are you going?
我找Lester有点事...
I gotta see Lester about...
这是什么?
What's all that?
五个区已知性犯罪者的假释信息
Parole info on known sex  offenders for five zip codes.
我桌上还有我们在5号码头抓到
I've also got background info on my desk
所有持手机人员的背景资料
for everyone we picked up at pier five with a cellphone.
- 你还真打算... - 根据FBI侧写
- You're actually gonna... - Compare the FBI profile
比对每个案件相关人员? 当然 总得有人干吧
with every person of interest I can find? Hell yeah, somebody's gotta.
- 过来 - 你搞什么?
- Come here. - The fuck are you doin'?
Maurice Dobey? 选州长? 我的州?
Maurice Dobey? For governor? Of my state?
我操
Shit.
这招玩得阴啊
That's some cynical politics, right there.
让明知不可能赢的人参选 想吓唬你破财消灾
Playin' like you gonna run a man you know can't win to scare people into payin' off.
Dobey能让你大出血啊 Tommy 巴尔的摩和PG县都是
Dobey could bloody you up, Tommy. In Baltimore and P.G. Both.
用田忌赛马那招 可耻
Playin' that race card. Shameful.
Upshaw要什么才肯置身事外?
What does Upshaw want to stay out of the race?
- 太多了 - 你准备给么?
- Too much. - Are you going to pay?
这么说吧 还在斡旋之中
Let's just say I'm in negotiations.
我会尽我所能防止这场暴乱扩散
I'll do everything I can to make sure this insurrection doesn't spread.
太好了 那么东区民主同盟的有力支持
Wonderful!And how  much is the loyal support
要我如何报答呢?
of the Eastside Democratic Coalition going to cost me?
只要您的市长推荐 既然这位兄弟屹立不倒
Only an endorsement, given that this man here is still standing,
我看Rupert Bond也没什么机会 挤进这间办公室了吧?
I don't believe that Rupert Bond is going to find his way into this office. Do you?
有了我的推荐 你们就会投桃报李
And for my endorsement, you will return the favour
无视我们乔治王子县的朋友
and ignore our friends in Prince George's.
那西区的忠诚又要我付出什么代价呢?
And the loyalty of the westside is going to cost me what exactly?
没啥大事 酒精管理委员会有三个空缺
Nothin' big. You got three seats comin' open on the liquor board.
- 给你一个席位 - 两个 我就帮你
- You get one seat. - Two an' you have me
在初选中筹集资金
raisin' money for you in the primary.
成交 想到你在酒管会有两票
Sold. And it scares me to think of the damage you can do
不知会怎么兴风作浪 我真是担心啊
with two votes on the liquor board.
- 这样不对 - 是啊 ...
- It ain't right. - No...
- 但是只能这样... - 不 你不能做这事儿
- It just is. - No, I mean, you can't do this.
做都做了 只要上头给钱
We're doing it. Whatever they give us to work the bullshit,
我就扔给Lester 或Crutchfield或Norris
I throw to Lester, or Crutchfield or Norris,
谁有该办的案子就扔给谁
anyone else who has a case that ought to be solved.
昨天让你跟我去Quantico白跑一趟 已经对不起你了
It's bad enough I wasted your day yesterday going to Quantico.
不能再让你白白浪费时间  你该办自己的入室谋杀案
I can't stand to see you wasting more time. You should be working your home invasion.
- Jimmy 你不能这么干 - 最多一两天
- Jimmy, you can't do this. - A couple days more,
等Lester抓到Marlo的罪证
and Lester gets his best shot at Marlo.
然后红丝带杀手就会销声匿迹
After that, we'll never hear from the red-ribbon killer again.
老大们慢慢失去兴趣 我假装再追查一两条线索
The bosses will lose interest, I'll pretend to run out a little more string,
然后一切受案交公 没什么危害
and then it goes right back to the admin office. No harm, no foul.
你那三尸案不管需要什么 Kima
Whatever you need, Kima, to work your triple
或者其他什么要紧案子
or any other case that matters to you.
人力 加班费 实验室 车辆
Manpower, O.T., lab work, cars.
跟我说一声就行
Just let me know.
我要走了
I gotta go.
买垃圾啊
Man! Junk!
旧报纸!
Old papers!
金属片!
Sheet metal!
收废品咯!
Junkman! Junk!
纸板箱
Cardboard.
- 报纸 - Bug 过来
- Newspapers. - Hey, Bug, up here.
10块钱我明天给你 你要是想找活干
I get you that ten tomorrow and if you're lookin' for work,
我倒是要人帮我抬东西
I got what needs liftin'.
你知道Bruce街上那个马棚? 九点前到
You know the stable on Bruce Street? Be there before nine.
呦 Duke 你收旧货了?
Dag, Duke, you a-rabbin' now?
这里显示5点15分34秒
I'm showing 5:15 and 34 seconds.
我在Park高地 在公园那儿把他给丢了
I'm up Park Heights but I lost him just past the park.
公交车冲上人行道撞到了根电线杆
MTA bus clipped the kerb and it knocked down a utility pole.
等我绕过去 他已经溜走了
By the time I detoured, he slipped me.
好 打给我
Well, let me know.
大消息
Big news.
Bunk有了Chris Partlow的谋杀逮捕令
Bunk has a murder warrant on Chris Partlow.
- 说什么哪 - 不是空屋案
- The hell you say. - Not one from the vacants.
DNA和街边殴打致死案匹配
DNA match on an alley beating.
他一动手 这帮家伙都会潜入地下
He lets this go now, these guys are gonna go to ground.
我们可是在要紧关头
We're right at the edge of something here.
他答应拖个几天
He's giving us a couple of days.
他欠我的 我帮他催了实验室报告
He owes me. I expedited his lab work for it.
- 还有Omar Little? 那个抢劫毒贩的? - 怎么了?
- And Omar Little? Stick up boy? - What about him?
在西区一家韩国杂货店中枪
Caught one in a Korean joint over westside.
Bunk从他兜里找到的 对我们有用不?
Bunk pulled that out of his pocket. Mean anything at all to us?
看来他是在追杀Marlo团伙啊
Looks like he was after Marlo's crew.
Cheese Cheese Wagstaff?
Cheese. Cheese Wagstaff?
除了站街角 他们还在全城做批发
In addition to their corners, these guys are wholesaling all over town,
我以为Cheese不过是一普通毒贩
so I figured Cheese was just one of many.
从这条子看Omar认定他是Marlo亲信
The note reads like Omar had him under Marlo's wing.
至少是个警督 我得走了
A lieutenant, at least. Anyway, I gotta go,
为了咱市还得继续装样子
do more pretending for the rest of the city.
对了 我告诉了Greggs
Oh, by the way, I - I told Greggs.
McNulty 你还要告诉多少人...
McNulty, how many more people...
她真准备去办连环杀手案
She was about to jump into the serial murders.
- 我不忍心看她瞎忙 - 她什么反应?
- I couldn't stand to spin her like that. - How'd she take it?
23-06呼叫23编组 正在重新定位目标
23-06 to any 23 sequence. Trying to reconnect with my subject.
- 有谁能帮忙的吗? - 23-15呼叫23-06
- Anyone who can assist? - 23-15 to 23-06.
我在2800街区 南Edgecombe环路
I'm in the 2800 block, Edgecombe Circle South,
盯着女性目标 可能你的人会前来此处
sitting on the female subject. Maybe that's the other end of your meet.
Edgecombe环路? 那是哪儿?
Edgecombe Circle? Where's that 20?
- 就在Pall Mall往下 - Pall Mall在哪儿?
- It runs off Pall Mall. - Where's Pall Mall?
- 我对西北区不太熟 - 就在Pimlico...
- I'm not too good up in the northwest. - Between Pimlico...
没关系 我查地图好了
Never mind, I got a map book.
好 看看在哪儿
OK, see what we got here.
34号地图 E3区域
Map 34, grid E3.
- 有什么发现? - 最后那钟显示啥?
- Whaddya got? - What'd that last clock show?
今晚与我同台的几位
And these people that I share the stage with tonight
代表了数百位
are here as representatives of the hundreds,
不 是数千位无家可归的市民
no, the thousands of citizens without shelter,
今晚在城里 毫无保护
without protection, in this city tonight.
为何非要这样呢?
Why does this have to be?
显然 过去的七年
Certainly, the last seven years
给美国城市带来的联邦福利
have not brought the same levels of federal commitment
远远不及前几任政府
to American cities as from previous administrations.
当然 州长在过去的一年中严格限制了
And certainly, our governor has in the last year placed severe restrictions
一些聊胜于无的州立项目
on whatever stopgap state programs were in place.
仅存下来的所谓安全网也已破败不堪
And what little remained of our  so-called safety net was simply shredded,
越来越多的同胞市民们
and more and more of our fellow citizens
发现自己置身于破碎的边缘 流浪街头
found themselves living life at the broken edges, in the street.
要我说这不仅是可悲 而是不可原谅!
Well, I say that this is not only tragic, it is unforgivable!
我来此是想说 决不能让这些人
And I am here to say that no longer can these people
这些和我同台的人成为透明人
with whom I share this  stage tonight be invisible,
就像本市所有无家可归人员
just as all of those without shelter in this city,
包括全国 都不该是透明的
in this country, can no longer be invisible to us.
很遗憾通过一名丧心病狂的犯罪者
And it is regrettable that it has taken the actions
的所作所为我们才开始反思
of a remorseless predator to make us reflect.
但我们巴尔的摩经受了考验
But we in Baltimore have been tested,
我们懂得了所有的市民
and we have been taught that all of our citizens
都应当享有法律的保护
deserve the full protection of the law,
都应当享有社区的支持
and the full support of the community.
我们警告这个冷血杀手
And we are saying to this senseless killer,
警告所有向本市流浪者伸出黑手的罪犯
and to all the other ills that prey on those without shelter in our city,
今晚你别想对他们下手
not tonight can you prey on them.
明天不行 永远不行
And not tomorrow. Not any longer.
我们会保护你们的!
We will protect you!
谢谢
Thank you.
她让你帮她搅拌着
She asked you keep that one stirred.
你是管我那事儿的吧?
You were on my thing, right?
看来我该请你喝一杯 你喝什么?
I guess I owe you a drink on that. What's your poison?
不用了 议员先生 非常感谢
I'm OK, senator, thank you very much.
Obonda? 干得漂亮啊
Obonda, huh? That's a good one.
你知道你推翻的大部分是我找的证据吧?
You know, that was mostly my evidence you beat back there, right?
- 还有种再来一次吗? - 你说什么?
- You think you could do that again? - Excuse me?
只不过这一次 陪审团换成联邦的
Except this time, the jury's a federal one.
比如 9个白人 3个黑人
Say, nine white, three black.
你该结账走人了 警官
Time for you to tip on out, detective.
几年前你购置Calvert县房产的
Bank records on that mortgage application
贷款申请银行记录
you made on the Calvert county property years back.
你还是老实告诉Billy Murphy吧?
Now, why don't you take that back to Billy Murphy?
问问你的律师该怎么办
Ask your attorney what you're exposed to.
目前此事就你知我知 参议员
At this point, this is just between us two gentlemen here, senator.
除非我说出去没人知道
And no one else till I make it so.
什么? 你还想用这案子敲诈我?
What? You tryin' to sell a case back to me?
妈的 你要...
Motherfucker, if you don't get...
我可不要这个钱
I don't get paid like that.
我领工资是为了过几天回来问你
I get paid when I come back in  a couple nights time with questions
你 先生 能给我老实回答
and you, sir, have answers.
不然我下个电话就打给联邦检察官
Or my next call will be  to the US Attorney's office,
咱们重新来过 这次玩真的
and we will go again. But for real.
这份你拿着好了
You can keep that copy. Ma'am.
告诉你一下 不管怎样这段导语要删掉
Just to let you know, before the fireworks start, I'm spiking this lead.
- 你会挺我吧? - 尽量
- But you got my back? - As best I can.
Scott
我要把你的导语删了
I'm spiking your lead.
我可不能发一篇公共集会的报道
I'm not running a story about a public gathering,
市政厅前的烛光悼念仪式
a candlelight vigil at City Hall, in fact,
这导语和引言居然出自一个匿名流浪者
where the lead anecdote and quote is from an unnamed homeless woman.
她不想让人知道她无家可归 我解释过了
She doesn't want to be known  as homeless.I explained that.
Scott 今晚那里有几百个流浪人员
Scott, there were hundreds of homeless down there tonight.
大家都是自愿参加活动的
People who voluntarily attended this event.
我想没有人会不愿意 让你把名字登出来的吧
And I'd guess that any number of them would've let you put their names in the paper.
但这故事多好啊 看她说的话
But her story is great. Look at that quote.
引言很好 简直太完美了
It's a perfect quote. Best quote I could ever ask for.
这正是我所担心的
That's my concern at this point.
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
你要是觉得是我编的 你可以去死了
To hell with you if you think I made it up.
我们有我们的规矩 我必须服从规矩
We have a standard that we follow here. And I'm gonna follow it.
麻烦来了 Gus
Here it comes, Gus.
对
Yep.
Gus 你要砍Scott守夜报道的开头?
Gus, you're retopping Scott's vigil copy?
- 没错 - 我觉得...
- I am. - But I thought...
公共集会中用匿名线索 没这个必要
Anonymous attribution in a public setting. There's no need for it.
- Gus 大家讨论下 - 已经讨论过了
- Gus, let's discuss this. - Actually, I did discuss it
和本市新闻主编讨论了 他也同意了
with the metro editor, and he agrees.
文章已经发到编辑部了
Now, the story's on the copy desk,
作为一个文字编辑 我已经尽职了
and as a line editor working this story, I feel I've done my job.
你作为主编 如果想对着干
Now, you as the M.E., if you want to go another way,
尽管把文章拿回来重新改
you pull the story back and re-edit.
但我们有引用政策 这我清楚
But we have a sourcing policy here, and I know it,
这种情况下我不想违背政策
and I do not feel comfortable bending the rules in this instance.
晚安
Good night.
喂?
Yeah?
McNulty 是Christeson
McNulty, it's Christeson.
我的案子搞定了 真要谢谢你
Listen, my case is down an' I wanted to thank you.
没了你还真不行
I couldn't have done it otherwise.
不客气
No problem.
- 讲得很好啊 - 孩子们睡了?
-It went great. - Kids asleep?
嗯 不过他们从W.B.A.L台看你了
Yeah, but they saw you on W.B.A.L.
Anna说你的头发看起来好滑稽
Anna said your hair looked funny.
能让她上心就好
Well, just so long as she was impressed.
C.N.N也在场
C.N.N. Was there.
不知道今晚会不会重播
I wonder if they'll cycle any coverage through tonight.
- 陛下今天状态不错呀? - 不好说
- A good day for hizzoner, huh? - I don't know.
Nerese逼我力保她参选市长
Nerese shook me down for a mayoral endorsement,
Clay Davis借尸还魂
and Clay Davis, back from the grave,
夺走了酒管委两个席位
took a couple of liquor board seats.
好容易才肯不倒戈PG县Upshaw的阵营
Just so as they won't join in Upshaw's war party in Prince George's.
你准备公开支持Nerese?  你不是说偏向Bond的嘛
You're gonna endorse Nerese? You told me you prefer Bond.
是 但Upshaw这事儿...
I do, but this thing with Upshaw...
说不定要送个大礼他才肯平息下来呢
Shit, I might even have to give him a bump just to calm him down.
天 他想要什么?
God. What's he asking?
- 有了  - Upshaw想要什么?
- There. Look. - What's Upshaw asking?
我从立法机关拿给巴尔的摩市
Half of any extra school or anti-crime money
一半的教育或执法经费都要给PG县
I get outta the legislature for Baltimore would go to P.G. County.
你要是同意 那你答应给巴尔的摩学校
You take that deal and Baltimore's out
的钱就少了一半了啊
half of what you want to bring back to the city schools.
是 但是我不赢 就什么也拿不到了
Yeah, but if I don't win, Jen, I bring back exactly nothing.
看
Look.
我们警告这个冷血杀手
And we are saying to this senseless killer,
警告其他妄图...
and to all the other ills...
去吧 快上床
Go on. Straight to bed.
孩子
Hey, kiddo.
你去哪儿了?
Where'd you go to?
跟你没关系 Jimmy
None of your business really, Jimmy.
下次 我哪儿都不去了
And next time, I'm not going anywhere.
下次 你给我卷铺盖滚 这儿是我家
Next time, you're gonna be out on your ass, because that's my fucking house.
干得漂亮 孩子
That's police work, son.
我拿出地图找一个地方
I pull the A.D.C. Book to find a location,
发现和秒针指的数字是一样的
and I'm on the same page number as the second hand.
我记得很多钟都是34秒
And I remember we had a lotta clocks with 34 seconds.
这页是西巴尔的摩
That's the page for West Baltimore.
对 既然知道秒针是地图页数
Right. Now, the second hand is always the map page.
经度A到K 是时针
Longitude, A-through-K, is the hour,
维度 他们用五分钟的间隔
and for the latitude, they go by five-minute intervals.
他们事先商量好碰面地点
Now they know the meeting spot in advance,
用密码标明地块
and they code it by the grid square.
但那钟面要是和时间无关
But if the clock has nothing to do with time,
他们怎么知道何时见面呢?
how do they know when to meet?
每处都在半小时车程之内 算上堵车
Everything's less than a half hour of driving, even in traffic.
我猜根据常理
My guess is that the standing logic
就是隔一小时左右碰头
is that they meet within an hour or so.
还有什么你知道嘛?
You know what else makes sense?
别人都不动的时候
This clock face when no one was on the move?
秒针都指向35秒
The times are all at 35 seconds.
这页是东Bawlmer
And that's the page for East Bawlmer.
- Cheese - Cheese Wagstaff?
- Cheese. - Cheese Wagstaff?
Marlo在西区通过Monk批发 东边通过Cheese
Marlo's wholesaling westside through Monk, and eastside with Cheese.
- 他把全市都拿下了 - 我们怎么知道是Cheese?
- He's got the whole goddamn city. - How do we know it's Cheese?
你也掺和进来了?
You, too, huh?
你们都觉得没什么吗?
You all are good with this?
Kima
我不同意
Not me.
那些你的酒友 Jimmy 那些姑娘们
All the guys at the bar, Jimmy, all the girls,
他们不会来参加你的追悼会的
they don't show up at your wake.
不是他们不喜欢你
Not because they don't like you
而是他们根本不知道你姓什么
but because they never knew your last name.
过了一个月 有人告诉他们 "哦 Jimmy死了"
A month later, someone tells 'em, "Oh, Jimmy died."
"哪个Jimmy?" "那个警察Jimmy"
"Jimmy who?" "Jimmy the cop."
"哦"他们说"他啊"
"Oh," they say. "Him."
所有跟你一块儿工作的人
And all the people on the job,
跟你一起整天坐车巡逻的人
all the people you spent all those hours in the radio car with,
他们只会把脚翘在台子上讲故事
the guys with their feet up on their desk telling stories,
谁欠了你饭钱 谁签了你加班工资单
who shorted you on the food runs, who signed your overtime slips.
但最后 他们也不会去的
In the end, they're not gonna be there either.
家庭 只有家庭 如果你够幸运
Family. That's it. Family, and if you're lucky,
一两个和家人一样的朋友
one or two friends who are the same as family.
这就是最好的结果了 其他都只是...
That's all the best of us get. Everything else is just...
没有连环杀手
There is no serial killer.
没有谋杀 都是我编的
There are no murders. I made it all up.
他们想停掉我们的调查 就这么...
They were shutting us down. They were just...
我也说不清
It's hard to explain.
我也不知道怎么就火了 我不知道该怎么停下来
I don't even know where the anger comes from, I don't know how to make it stop.
他们把我逼急了 真的
They fucking task me, they do.
我们把拨给我们调查的钱
We took the money from the bullshit investigation,
转给Lester
and rerouted it to Lester.
现在他有资源拿下Marlo Stanfield了
Now he's got the cake to take down Marlo Stanfield.
现在我做了这些 看着我自己这么干
And now that I've done all this, now that I've watched myself do it,
我都看不下去...
I can't even stand to...
Lester说已经快了
Lester says he's close.
时间一到 我就能把这事结了
Time will pass, and I'll be able to shut this thing down.
除非你能不进监狱
If you don't go to jail.
你无权这样做
You had no fucking right.
- 我知道 - 这也是我的生活
- I know. - This is my life, too.
一开始编故事 觉得自己是个英雄
You start to tell the story; you think you're the hero.
等到能说的说完了 你就...
And then,when you get done talking, you...
姓 Little 名 Omar 非裔美国人